<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Assistive-Robotics on Accessible IoT</title><link>https://accessible-iot.org/themes/assistive-robotics/</link><description>Recent content in Assistive-Robotics on Accessible IoT</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://accessible-iot.org/themes/assistive-robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spread Your Wings: Demonstrating a Soft Floating Robotic Avatar with Flapping Wings for Novel Physical Interactions</title><link>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/xu2025spread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/xu2025spread/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This demonstration presents a soft floating robotic avatar with flapping wings that enables novel forms of physical interaction. The robot builds on previous work (Cuddle robot) to explore how wing-based movements can create engaging and affective human-robot interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cuddle-Fish: Exploring a Soft Floating Robot with Flapping Wings for Physical Interactions</title><link>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/xu2025cuddle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/xu2025cuddle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cuddle-Fish presents an innovative soft floating robot with flapping wings designed for safe physical interactions. The soft materials and gentle motion make it suitable for therapeutic and assistive applications, particularly in contexts requiring calming, non-threatening robotic presence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I am both here and there</title><link>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/barbareschi2023robotic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://accessible-iot.org/publications/barbareschi2023robotic/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking study conducted in a real café environment where disabled workers operated multiple robotic avatars in parallel. The research demonstrates that people with disabilities possess specific competencies that enhance their ability to manage multiple embodied presences simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings have significant implications for employment opportunities and workplace accessibility, showing how assistive robotics can create new forms of meaningful work for people with mobility impairments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was featured in multiple accessibility newsletters and demonstrates the practical application of IoT and robotics in creating inclusive workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>